<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automation on Helix&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://helixspiral.github.io/tags/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automation on Helix&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://helixspiral.github.io/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multi-arch Docker builds with Rust</title>
      <link>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2023-06-16-rust-multiarch-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2023-06-16-rust-multiarch-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been playing with some Rust projects, and one of the biggest struggles I had was getting a small platform agnostic Docker image that I could use to build any platform using docker buildx.
The code I wrote a very small program that spits out a random number along with the current architecture to use as an sample for our Docker work.
use rand::Rng; use current_platform::CURRENT_PLATFORM; fn main() { let mut rng = rand::thread_rng(); let r_num: u8 = rng.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomy Picture of the Day Notification Service</title>
      <link>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2022-07-26-astronomy-picture-of-the-day-notification-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2022-07-26-astronomy-picture-of-the-day-notification-service/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this blog we&amp;rsquo;ll cover how the Astronomy Picture of the Day microservices are built and deployed with Docker and Kubernetes, and how to deploy the lightweight MQTT broker Mosquitto.
This is a follow up to my previous blog post System Scalability and Microservices with some additional information.
Requirements Docker installed locally Working Kubernetes cluster Helm installed GitHub repositories All of the code relating to this blog post can be found at the following links and is released under the GPL-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Scalability and Microservices</title>
      <link>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2022-02-28-system-scalability-and-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2022-02-28-system-scalability-and-microservices/</guid>
      <description>Overview This blog will talk about system scalability with relation to microservices and how a monolithic application would be less desired in this example.
GitHub repositories All of the code relating to this blog post can be found at the following links and is released under the GPL-3.0 license, with the exception of the official NASA api which is released under the Apache-2.0 license.
Official NASA APOD API - The official NASA API for getting the Astronomy Picture of the Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring backwards compatibility in deployments by leveraging git tags</title>
      <link>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2021-04-02-using-git-tags-to-ensure-deployment-backwards-compability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2021-04-02-using-git-tags-to-ensure-deployment-backwards-compability/</guid>
      <description>Overview I recently came across a blog post on injecting variables into Golang at build time and that gave me the idea for this blog post. Automating versioning and ensuring backwards compatibility.
GitHub repository and sample application You can find the code for this application here, on my GitHub
Git tags and versioning This blog post assumes some basic understanding of the git version control system. For anyone new to it you can probably get by with thinking that commits are incremental changes to the software and tags are user-created labels that reference a specific commit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Kubernetes with Saltstack</title>
      <link>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2020-10-13-automating-kubernetes-with-saltstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2020-10-13-automating-kubernetes-with-saltstack/</guid>
      <description>Overview My goal for this project was to setup and manage a Kubernetes cluster using Saltstack, the idea being that since I wanted to learn them both if I could automate the setup of the cluster I&amp;rsquo;d be killing two birds with one stone.
I found a few good blog posts on this but all the ones I found lacked the level of automation I was looking for, some had hard coded values and others had manual commands needing to be run on the minions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
