<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grpc on Helix&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://helixspiral.github.io/tags/grpc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grpc on Helix&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://helixspiral.github.io/tags/grpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automated certificate management in local Kubernetes clusters, with local domains</title>
      <link>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2024-12-19-kubernetes-tls-certificates-with-local-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2024-12-19-kubernetes-tls-certificates-with-local-domains/</guid>
      <description>Overview / Requirements / Setup After setting up external-dns and cert-manager for the hundreth time I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to add some functionality to my homelab cluster and have proper signed certs there. This blog post is a basic outline of how to setup cert-manager to sign certificates using a certificate and key provided from an intermediary CA.
I&amp;rsquo;m using pfSense to both provide DNS to my .lan domain and generate the root and intermediary CA certs, you can use whatever platform you&amp;rsquo;d like but the steps outlined here use pfSense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Coop Tech</title>
      <link>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2024-01-19-chicken-coop-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helixspiral.github.io/posts/2024-01-19-chicken-coop-tech/</guid>
      <description>Overview Over the end of year 2023 Holidays I had a vacation and started working on revamping some tech for my chicken coop. This blog post is going to detail what we had initially, what I&amp;rsquo;m building, and some future ideas for the chicken tech.
Equipment/Software Used Original Helium Hotspot - Any official Helium Hotspot1 or home-built Data-Only2 hotspot will work SenseCAP 2103 (2)3 - LoRaWAN Temp, Humidity, and CO2 Sensor Raspberry PI 4b 8GB (2) - Local k8s cluster running in my home Helium Console4 - Helium Network console provided by the Helium Foundation, but any Helium-compatible console will work SenseCAP-Decoder5 - Javascript function for decoding 210X sensors provided by SenseCAP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
